Guide to the Philip G. Zimbardo Papers SC0750
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Teaching files, Series 7
  Lecture courses include: Introduction to Psychology The Psychology of Mind Control Social Psychology (taught solo and also as a co-teacher) Social Psychology In Action Social Alienation The Nature of Madness The Psychology of Hypnosis Sex Roles in the U.S. and Italy (During Florence teaching term) Cross-Cultural Psychology (During Florence teaching term) Psychology and Drama (Co-taught with Patricia Ryan, Drama Department)
  Seminars include: The Psychology of Imprisonment (Co-taught with Carlo Prescott, ex convict) The Dynamics of Shyness Practicum in Teaching (graduate and undergraduate) Collective Violence (co-taught with Bob Zajoc) The Psychology of Time Perspective (Sophomore Seminars) On Becoming a Professional Psychologist (for advanced graduate students) Effective Teaching (Co-taught with David Rosenhan) Research Methods in Social Psychology (Graduate Course) Research Issues in Social-Cognitive Pathology (Graduate Course) Graduate Pro-seminar in Social Psychology (Weekly Area Meetings, Faculty and Graduate Students) The Dynamics of Shyness (Freshman Seminars) Senior Psychology Majors' Proseminar
  For more information, please visit http://www.zimbardo.com/teaching
  Zimbardo began teaching at Stanford University in 1968. His introductory psychology course has since been one of the most popular offerings for undergraduate students. The teaching files series includes course materials such as syllabi, exams, lecture notes, and research materials used for lecture preparation.
  - Course readers
  - Handout for TA's on Women's Voices (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Teaching tips (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Award Noms, Zimbardo, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Innovative Teaching (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Conf Contacts, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Electronic Univ Telecourse (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Book Correspondence, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Feedback - Teaching and General, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - A Passion for Psychology: Teaching it Charismatically, Integrating Teaching... (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - A. Zimbardo Minority Students, 1989, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - A. Zimbardo Influences, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Zimbardo, B. Teaching Method Material, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Zimbardo, C. Research - Teaching (empty) (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Zimbardo, D. Curricula/Courses, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Zimbardo, E. Classroom Performance, 1989-2000 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Zimbardo, F. Teacher Training, 1989-2000 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Zimbardo, G. Teaching Methods Practice, 1993-1998 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Zimbardo's Teaching, Circa 1993 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Practicum in Teaching, Psy 003, Winter 2000, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Psychology 1-2001 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Handouts- Prof Psych. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Psych 257 sections, Teaching Practicum, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Meyer AV/Video- Mind/Brain, 1992 Dec 18 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Helping Students Handouts (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Ethics (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Psych & Life (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Academic Jobs (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Teaching of Psych (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - The Compleat Academic (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - An Academic Woman (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Jobs (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Professional Psych Class (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Academic Jobs & Job Search (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Academic Job Search (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - Psych 288, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Pratto- '93 Social, 1992-1993 (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - Modules for WGBH, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Review by Stephen J. Kraus, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Re: Discovering Psychology (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Discovering Psych (1) (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Discovering Psych (2) (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Invitations to teach winter/spring '97, 1996-1997 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Mind Control 1990 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Discovering Psych Video Guide, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Shyness & Job Search (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Mind Control, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Mind Control Course Evals (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Final-199, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Notes 1997, Psych 1 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Mind Control Course Eval, sp. 95, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Psych 164, Mind Control, Winter 1997 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Mind Control Syllabus, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Shyness, Social Phobia (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Shyness Seminar (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Freshman Seminar, Shyness, Spring 2000 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Frosh/Soph Program, 1999/2000 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Freshman Seminar- Spring 99, Zimbardo - Shyness, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Psych 196, Handouts (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Psychology 196 - Fall 2000 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Psych 196-Fall 1999, Contemporary Issues & Research in Psychology, Special Proseminar... (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Psych. 196 - Readings (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Psych 196- Readings (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Time Perspective, Psych 181B, Spring 1995 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Time Perspective Seminar 1996 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Social Psychology, Psych 121, Fall, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Psych 590 Social Psych - team taught w/ Steele & Pratto, 1995-1996 (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Psychology of Mind Control, Psych 199, Spring 1995 (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Social Psych. - Basic Lecture (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - Social Psychology General Teaching Materials (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - Guest, Possible For Class, 2003 (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - For Professional Psych Course, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Prof. Psych/Vita, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Prof Psych, Circa 1996 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Grants (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Prof. Psych (student info) (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Psy 288, Prof. Psychologist, Fall 1994 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Vita (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Psych 314 Intro & Syllabus, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Psych 314, Politics & The English Language (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Psych 314, Information you should have about the school of your choice, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Psych 314, Lists of Readings (empty) (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Psych 314, An Introduction to the Hiring Process in Academic Psychology (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Psych 300, Professional Psychologists Evaluations, w. 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Psych 300, Professional Psychologists, Winter 1973 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Plous: Prof Psychologist (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Scientific Writing Tips (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Teaching Behaviors (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Professional Psychology (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Psych 314, The Presentation: Testing Potential New Faculty's Ability to Teach, 1974-circa 1987 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Psych 314, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, a/1981/1982 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Articles on Academics/Teachers (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Psych 314, Course Syllabus 1981/82 & Selling Yourself to an Employer, 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Student Research Paper Evaluation Form (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Prof. Psych - Course - Ethics in Academic Research, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Prof. Psych Course - Edited MS (Box 45, Folder 25)
  - Writing the Journal Article (Box 45, Folder 26)
  - Colloquium, How to Give One (Box 45, Folder 27)
  - Report On Teaching (Box 45, Folder 28)
  - Notes About Classes (Box 45, Folder 29)
  - Psych 314, F 84/5, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, Between Scientists & Public, Communcating Psychological Research Through the Mass Media, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 30)
  - Psych 314, Between Scientists & Public, Communicating Psychological Research Through the Mass Media, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 31)
  - Psych 300, WPA Info (Box 45, Folder 32)
  - Psych 314, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, F 82/83, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 33)
  - Psych 314, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, Professional Careers in Psychology, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 34)
  - Psych 314, Some rather obvious, though rarely followed, suggestions pertinent to getting a job... (Box 45, Folder 35)
  - Psych 314, F 84/85, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, Information you should have about the school of your choice, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 36)
  - Psych 314, Tenure Itch, Cornell Alumni News, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 37)
  - Psych 314, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, BUCKNELL UNIV., Joint Appointment w/ Andrea and Ian. 4/2/82, 1982 Apr 2 (Box 45, Folder 38)
  - Psych 314, F 84/85, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, The Presentation: Testing Potential of New Faculty's Ability to Teach, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 39)
  - Psych 314, Writing the Empirical Joural Article in Psych: A Checklist of Accumulated Wisdom, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 40)
  - Mentoring of Female Students by Faculty (Teaching professional psychology) (Box 45, Folder 41)
  - Psych 315, Professional Psychologists, Student Vitae (Box 45, Folder 42)
  - Psych 314, On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, Sample Vita (Sigmund Freud) (Box 45, Folder 43)
  - Prof. Psychologist Course (Box 45, Folder 44)
  - Psych 314, material 1984/85, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 45)
  - Psych 314, Now's the time to get organized. psych 314 fall 84/5, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 46)
  - Psych 314, F 84/5, Terms Useful in Perfomance Evaluation and their meanings, 1984-1985 (Box 45, Folder 47)
  - Psych 314, Professional Careers in Psychology (Box 45, Folder 48)
  - Psych 314 Bucknell Contract (Box 45, Folder 49)
  - Psych 314 Pentagon plan aims at luring stends into military-related Ph.D programs, 1981 Sep 2 (Box 45, Folder 50)
  - Notes on prof. psychology field (Box 45, Folder 51)
  - Psych 314, Terms Useful in Performance Evaluation and their Meanings (Box 45, Folder 52)
  - Psych 314 vitae (Box 45, Folder 53)
  - 1982-83 professional psych course evals, 1982-1983 (Box 45, Folder 54)
  - Pscyh 314 S. Porter "How to Prepare for the Interviews" (Box 45, Folder 55)
  - Psych 314 F 84/85 On Becoming a Professional Psychologist (2 units) (Box 45, Folder 56)
  - Psych 314, Memo re letters of recommendation (Box 45, Folder 57)
  - Psych 314- Papers (Box 45, Folder 58)
  - Over, R. - Collaborative Research & Publication in Psychology (Box 45, Folder 68)
  - How to Give a Colloquium (Box 45, Folder 59)
  - Darley, John M & Zanna, Mark P - An Introduction to the Hiring Process in Academic Psychology (Box 45, Folder 60)
  - Bumpus, Frank J - Career Vitality of Professors: A Cognitive Restructuring Model, 1983 Apr 27-30 (Box 45, Folder 61)
  - Kalin, R. & Grant, B. A. - Sex Differences in Employments... (Box 45, Folder 62)
  - Kalin, R. & Grant. B. A. - Sex Differences in Employment... (Box 45, Folder 63)
  - Darley, J. M. & Zanna, Mark P. - An Introduction to the Hiring Process in Academic Psychology (Box 45, Folder 64)
  - Unger, R. K. - Sexism in teacher evaluation... (Box 45, Folder 65)
  - Unger, R. K. - Sexism in teacher evaluation... (Box 45, Folder 66)
  - Over, R. - Collaborative Research & Publication in Psychology (Box 45, Folder 67)
  - Iacono, William G. - the Academic Job Search:... (Box 45, Folder 69)
  - Iacono, William G. - the Academic Job Search:... (Box 45, Folder 70)
  - Psych 314, F 84/5, Memos on Letters of Recommendation (Box 45, Folder 71)
  - Prof Psych Course, 1984 Oct 16 (Box 45, Folder 72)
  - The Art of Discussion, 1979 Sep 28 (Box 45, Folder 73)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control: Readings in Persuasion, Influence, Indoctrination, and Conversion (Volume I), 1997 (Box 46, Volume 1)
  - Psy164(2) Psych of Mind Control Reader (1) Vol II, 1997 (Box 46, Volume 2)
  - Psy164 Psych of Mind Control Reader (2) Vol II, 1997 (Box 46, Volume 3)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control: Readings, 1991 (Box 46, Volume 4)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control: Readings (Philip Zimbardo with Rose McDermott), 1990 (Box 46, Volume 5)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control: Readnigs, Sections 1-3 (Philip Zimbardo) (Box 46, Volume 6)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control: Readnigs, Sections 4-6 (Philip Zimbardo) (Box 46, Volume 7)
  - Persuasion, Coercion, Indoctrination, and Mind Control (Philip Zimbardo and Robert Vallone), 1983 (Box 46, Volume 8)
  - Psy 121 (Pratto/Steele/Zimbardo) course reader., 1995 (Box 46, Volume 9)
  - The Psychology of Time Perspective Course Reader, 1996 (Box 46, Volume 10)
  - The Psychology of Time Perspective, psychology 181A (Zimbardo) Volume I, 1992-1993 (Box 46, Volume 11)
  - The Psychology of Time Perspective, psychology 181A (Zimbardo) Volume II, 1992-1993 (Box 46, Volume 12)
  - Candid Camera Classica in Introductory Psychology, viewer's guide/instructor's manual (Zimbardo w/ Allen Funt), 1985 (Box 46, Volume 13)
  - "I'm so Excited!" The Effects of Music on Rumor Distortion (Mike Sego and Michael Kives), 2000 Mar 10 (Box 46, Volume 14)
  - Student Evaluations Psych. 1, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Demonstrations-Psych 1, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Psych 001 TA Evaluations Sp 84/85, 1984-1985 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Psych 001 Sp. 84/85 Feedback (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Psych 1 Course Evaluations, 1977, 1982-1983 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Practicum in Teaching 2001 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Psych 1 TA Materials, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Ideas for Psych 1 TAs (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Section Leader Evaluations, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Individuation (for psych and drama class), 1989 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Memory (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Q-Day Consent Win 89, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Psych 1 (empty) (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Psych 1 (empty) (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Psych 1- Business (spring 1990) (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Lecture Notes - Psych 1 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Cults/Psych 1 - section, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Exploratorium Exhibit (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Psych 1 TA evals, winter '93, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Psych 1 syllabi, winter 1994 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Psych 1 - 1994 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Winter '94. Psych 1, Exam #3, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Winter '94 Psych 1 Exam #2, form 1 & 2, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Winter '94 Psych 1 Exam #1, form 1 & 2, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Psych 1 Spring 1996 Evaluations (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Psych 1 Spring 1996 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Evaluations-- Fall, 1996 (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - Psych 1 Spring 1997 Evaluations (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Edith Eva Eger, Guest Lecturer, Spring, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control Winter 1997 - Evaluations (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - The Psychology of Mind Control Winter Quarter 1997 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Psych 1 Spring 98 Evaluations, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Psych 1 Spring 98, TA's & TA Related Info, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Psych 1 Spring 98 Guest Lecturers, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - Psych 1 Stuff, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - Psych 1 Spring 98 Miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Psych 1 Spring 98 Schedule, Syllabus, Book Info, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 37)
  - Psych 1 - Spring 1998 (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Psych 1 Sp 98 handouts, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Psych 1 Winter 00 Evaluations, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2000 Handouts, Class Notes, ETC. (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2000, Guest Lecturers (Box 47, Folder 42)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2000 Syllabus, Schedule, Book Info (Box 47, Folder 43)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2000 TA's (Box 47, Folder 44)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2000 Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 45)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2000 Hypnotizability Scores (empty) (Box 47, Folder 46)
  - Psych 1 2000 (Box 47, Folder 47)
  - Psych 1 Book Sales Jan 2000, 2000 Jan (Box 47, Folder 48)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2001 Syllabus, Schedule, Book Info (Box 47, Folder 49)
  - Psych 1 Winter 2001 TA's (Box 47, Folder 50)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2001 BOOK SALES (Box 47, Folder 51)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2001 Guest Lecturers (Box 47, Folder 52)
  - Psych 1, 2001 Handouts, Class Notes, Etc. (Box 47, Folder 53)
  - Psych 1, Winter 2001 Miscellaneous (2001) (Box 47, Folder 54)
  - Psych 1 Spring 03, 2003 (Box 47, Folder 55)
  - Psych 1 - spring 2003, SCHEDULE & SYLLABUS (Box 47, Folder 56)
  - Psych 1 - Spring 2003, TA's (Box 47, Folder 57)
  - Psych 1 - Spring 2003, Guest Lecturers (Box 47, Folder 58)
  - Exploring Human Nature, Zimbardo, Winter 2004, General Information (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - PSY 187 Exploring Human Nature, Guests (W 2004) (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Psych 1 Winter 1999 TA's (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Practicum in Teaching, Winter 1999, Psych 003 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Practicum W99 Evaluations, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Psych 1 Winter 99 Evaluations, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Hypnotizability Scores, Psych 1--1999 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Psych 1 Book Sales, Jan 1999, 1999 Jan (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Psych 1, Winter 1999 Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Psych 1, Winter 1999 Guest Lecturers (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Psych 1, Winter 1999 Handouts, Class Notes, Etc. (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Psych 1, Winter 1999 Syllabus, Schedule, Book Info (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Commendations for Teaching, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Teaching - Fan Letters and Letters of Appreciation (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Letters to/from Phil (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Teaching Feedback (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Teaching - Development/Honors, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Teaching - Honor Code, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - On Teacher Liberation: Pedagogy with Passion, PGZ from Instructor's R. M. (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Teaching - SFSU Teaching Project (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Teaching - Student Correspondence (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Teaching to TA's (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Teaching Records (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Annual Report, 1995 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Appointments, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Teaching Workshop Certificates (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Case of Struwwelpeter (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Case Study of Mr. F.B. (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - FB Case-Final Evaluation (Box 48, Folder 29)
  - Depression/Mr. F.B. (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Using Videos 1993 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Workshops on Teaching, 1992 Mar 14 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Teaching - Correspondence (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - "On creating the teachable moment..." talk (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Psych 170 383/84 Psychology & Control Psych 170/ Drama 124 Seminar- Syllabus, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Psych 1, 1970, Final Exam (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - Harvard Group Scale of Hypnotic Susceptibility (Box 48, Folder 37)
  - Feedback (extra copies) (Box 48, Folder 38)
  - Teaching-Perception-Ames Illusion (Box 48, Folder 39)
  - Cognitive Control (teaching materials for student handouts) (Box 48, Folder 40)
  - P.G. Zimbardo Quotable Quotes, 11/7/77, 1977 Nov 7 (Box 48, Folder 41)
  - Alex Armour Elegy 4/15/83, 1983 Apr 15 (Box 48, Folder 42)
  - Social Psych - 121, Spring '71: Course Outline (Special course out of which the prison exp. emerged, during student strike), 1971 (Box 48, Folder 43)
  - Frosh Talk (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - Frosh Talk "Will I Make It?", 1969, 1969 Sep 26 (Box 48, Folder 45)
  - SUPA - Fundraising (Stanford Undergrad. Psych. Assoc.) (Box 48, Folder 46)
  - Psychology 1 Finals, Winter 1970 (Special type of exam) (Box 48, Folder 47)
  - Zim - Vita & Pub. Changes (empty) (Box 48, Folder 48)
  - Doss, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Doss Case Materials (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Suicide- Past Sections (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - W2001: Suicide II (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Suicide- Materials (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Winter 2001: Suicide (more materials to distribute) #1 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Suicide Readings (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Datek (clinical interventions reading) (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Guilt/Deception Section - exercise handouts/materials (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Witner 2001: Memory (materials for TA I) (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Psych 1 - Memory Transparancies (2), W2001 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Psych 1- Memory Transparencies (4), W2001 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Psych 1, Spring 2003, Suicide Section Evals (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Experiments and Demonstrations (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Psych 1 Term Papers, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Teaching Introductory Psych (survival tips by the experts) (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Lecture Launchers, PGZ's lecuter ideas (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Lecture Materials from Psych & Life (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - TA Impressions, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Transparencies set 5, Impressions, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Who am I? Materials (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Winter 2001: Detecting Guilt & Deceptions, 2001 Feb 5 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Detecting Guilt & Deception - Past Sections (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Guilt Lie Detection - Readings (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - (1) CSPP, (2) Commencement Talk, Lick-Wilmerding HS, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Peace SU Strike Activities 1970, 1970 May (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Florence Villa Courses (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Shyness Mail (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Psych 1, Evil, 1972 Oct (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Cult Chapter/Hartley, 1983-1984 (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Psych 199 Mind Control W 86/87 Final Exam (2 copies), 1986 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings: brainwashing and cults, Circa 1993 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - "Social action as teh control of affect" by David Heise (1977) (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - "The Con Man and his Lingo" by David Maurer, 1940 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - "A self-image analysis fo persuasion adn attitude involvement" by Michael R. Leippe (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Zimbardo: "Most Cult Members Come From Mainstream America" (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Mind control course- papers, 1990 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Mind Control (misc. course materials), 1990 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - "Readings in Cross-Cultural Communication", 1984 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Psychology of Attitude Change and Social Influence (book), 1990 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Survival/Jones, 1981 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - "Inadvertent Hypnosis During Interrogation and the Satanic Cult Myth..." by Richard J. Ofshe (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Mind Control Articles (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Psych 199 Mind Control W 86/87, Midterm Exam Complete w/ case study transcript, guidelines for scoring and answer key, 1986 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous mind control- lecture slides, notes, syllabus, etc. (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Cultic Studies Journal, spring/summer '85, 1985 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - various articles- human behavior etc. (Box 69, Folder 17)
  - Mind control course materials (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - Scientology- test stuff, 1991 May 8 (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - Jeanne Mills' talk to psych 1 class, 1979 May 23 (Box 69, Folder 20)
  - Mind Control TA Materials, 1990 (Box 69, Folder 21)
  - Public Mind, Bill Moyers, 1989 (Box 69, Folder 22)
  - Mind Control Syllabus/Reader, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 23)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 1 (Box 69, Folder 24)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 2 (Box 69, Folder 25)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 3 (Box 69, Folder 26)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 4 (Box 69, Folder 27)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 5 (Box 69, Folder 28)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 6 (Box 69, Folder 29)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 7 (Box 69, Folder 30)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 8 (Box 69, Folder 31)
  - Mind Control (1991) Lecture 9 (Box 69, Folder 32)
  - Meyer Media Center (list of videos for class), 1991 (Box 69, Folder 33)
  - Mind Control (1990) course syllabus/lecture schedule (Box 69, Folder 34)
  - Psych 199 (mind control, 1993)- course materials (Box 69, Folder 35)
  - Psych 199 course materials (1993)- midterm, slides, articles (Box 69, Folder 36)
  - Mind Control (1995) Course slides, articles (Box 69, Folder 37)
  - Mind Control Newspaper Articles (Box 69, Folder 38)
  - Cults- mind control article (Box 69, Folder 39)
  - "Understanding Mind Control" by Zimbardo & Andersen, 1993 (Box 69, Folder 40)
  - Mind Control- '95, 1995 (Box 69, Folder 41)
  - "Fragile Realities: The Psychology of Ideological Conversion in Cults and other Powerful Groups" by Leslie Downing (March, 1995), 1995 Mar (Box 69, Folder 42)
  - John Steiner + Holocaust pieces, 1995 May (Box 69, Folder 43)